RAJENDRA PATEL

Senior QA Analyst

Brampton, Ontario L6V 4R8 | +1 647-674-7091 | patelraj112@gmail.com

CAREER SUMMARY:

A Software Quality Assurance experience in all phases of the software testing life cycle that includes Test strategies, executing Test plans, designing Test cases, defect management, developing Automation scripts, and implementing a framework for software products.

Having academic solid credentials including Masters in Computer Engineering with hands-on technology experience accustomed to working in complex, project-based environments inAgile/Scrum as well as in Waterfall methodology.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Klick Inc

Senior QA Analyst | April 2019 - Present

- Daily status meetings with Business, Project management and Developers during all stages of the Software Development Life Cycle.
- Create requirements traceability matrices and conduct reviews with business analysts and technical development staff to ensure understanding of business requirements and complete test coverage
- Develop detailed work plans, schedules, project estimates, resource plans, and status reports specific to the QA effort
- Creates the Test Plan for the software release, defining resources, and test suites required for each test cycle, dependencies, risks, and the overall strategy for testing complex systems or applications
- Escalates issues and risks to project leadership in accordance with best practices
- Directs the software test automation effort by developing formal test cases to ensure that there is an adequate level of coverage for all required application
- Design, develop, and execute automation scripts using Selenium & Java

Busy QA

QA Analyst | July 2018 - March 2019

- Worked with the BA and Development team to understand the requirements and design of the application.
- Performing mobile testing using Emulators and Real Devices to meet the required mobile testing requirements in Android and iOS.
- Work with team to ensure execution of smoke, functional and regressions tests in all levels
 of the environments
- Testing existing system processes and provide recommendations for improvements
- Design and develop test cases to ensure products meet all functional and designrequirements

Staunchsys IT Services

QA Automation Engineer | Sep 2014 - June 2018

- Daily status meetings with Business, Project management and Developers during all stages of the Software Development Life Cycle.
- · Hands-on execution of test cases, update the documentation accordingly with results
- Schedules and performs functional, integration, regression and release testing
- Use QA software tools for defect management, regression, and automation
- Executes manual and automated test cases that validate the functionalities, code quality and reports test results
- Reviews functional requirements and determines the data requirements for executing the
 use cases end to end from creating functional manual cases to automating the cases for
 regression.
- Developed Automated Test Scripts from Manual Test Cases for Regression Testing.
- Testing web-based applications on Mobiles / Desktop

DOLPHIN WEB SOLUTION PVT. LTD

QA Analyst | Jube 2013 - Aug 2014

- Designed Test Matrices, Test Cases and Test Scripts according to business requirements and specifications.
- Review and use the BRD as the main document to create all test documentation
- Contribute to the development of End to End Testing
- Develops detailed unit, user-acceptance and regression test cases
- Submits defects and issues to development for correction, and retests once defects havebeen resolved

EDUCATION:

2011 - 2013 | Ganpat University

Master in Computer Engineering

SKILLS:

- Analytical and problem-solving
- Software testing lifecycles
- Functional Automation using Selenium & Java
- API Testing
- Testing web-based applications on Mobiles / Desktop
- Accessbilitty testing